{
    "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
    "name": "Welding: Part C",
    "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
    "questions": [
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Which term describes the voltage output of the machine while you are welding?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "amperage",
                "high frequency voltage",
                "arc voltage",
                "open circuit voltage"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["arc voltage"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "The main function of which device is to change AC to DC?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "resistor",
                "rectifier",
                "relay",
                "reactor"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["rectifier"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Which term describes the NEMA rating of a welding machine?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "duty cycle",
                "direct current",
                "arc voltage",
                "amperage"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["duty cycle"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Electrode negative is the same as:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "straight polarity",
                "reverse polarity",
                "high frequency",
                "alternating current"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["straight polarity"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Which term describes a noisy, uncontrollable arc that flares from side to side?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "arc voltage",
                "arc blow",
                "inductance",
                "resistance"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["arc blow"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Which current flows in one direction only and has either a positive or negative value?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "direct current",
                "alternating current",
                "pulse current",
                "high frequency current"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["direct current"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Which term expresses the strength of a current of electricity?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "amperage",
                "voltage",
                "duty cycle",
                "ohm"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["amperage"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "When no current is flowing in the circuit, but the machine is on, you can measure the:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "constant current",
                "open circuit voltage",
                "alternating current",
                "arc voltage"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["open circuit voltage"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "The speed at which AC changes direction is the:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "voltage",
                "amperage",
                "frequency",
                "resistance"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["frequency"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "In welding, what do you create when enough amperage and voltage exist to overcome the natural resistance to the flow of the electricity?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "amperage",
                "voltage",
                "high frequency",
                "an arc"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["an arc"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Which term describes the typical sound of an AC transformer welding machine?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "turbine whine",
                "high-pitched scream",
                "buzz box",
                "whisper quiet"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["buzz box"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Which type of welding machine is capable of changing DC to high frequency AC?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "AC generator",
                "DC rectifier",
                "DC generator",
                "Inverter"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Inverter"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Choose the largest cable size.",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "4",
                "2/0",
                "3/0",
                "4/0"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["4/0"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "How do you rate electrode holders?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "by voltage carrying capacity",
                "by maximum electrode size",
                "by amperage carrying capacity",
                "by the size of welding cable"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["by amperage carrying capacity"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Loose work lead connections when using SMAW may cause:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "electrical shock",
                "magnetic arc blow",
                "high burn-off rates",
                "arcing at the work clamp"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["arcing at the work clamp"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "An advantage to using a magnetic work lead device over a spring-loaded clamp is that the magnetic connection:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "effectively prevents arc blow",
                "is less likely to damage the work piece",
                "is a permanently attached connection",
                "can attach to all metals"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["is less likely to damage the work piece"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "If the welding cable connected to the machine is 1/0, then the whip cable should be what size?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "4/0",
                "3/0",
                "2/0",
                "2"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["2"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Who writes the electrode specifications?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "ABSA and WCB",
                "ASTM and NEMA",
                "CSA and AWS",
                "ASME and NEMA"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["CSA and AWS"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "In the AWS classification for SMAW mild steel electrodes, what does the last digit represent?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "the type of shielding gas produced by the melting flux",
                "the amount of iron powder that is added to the coating",
                "the welding position in which the electrode may be satisfactorily operated",
                "the major ingredient in the coating and the recommended current for best results"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["the major ingredient in the coating and the recommended current for best results"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "What do the first two digits in the AWS classification for carbon steel SMAW electrodes represent?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "current type and application",
                "minimum as-welded tensile strength of the weld deposit",
                "recommended welding positions",
                "iron powder content of the coating in %"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["minimum as-welded tensile strength of the weld deposit"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "In the CSA numbering system for welding electrodes, what does the prefix letter E represent?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "electronic",
                "energized",
                "electrode",
                "electromotive force"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["electrode"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "According to AWS, which number indicates the recommended positions for a E7024 electrode?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "first number",
                "second number",
                "third number",
                "fourth number"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["third number"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "The CSA system uses what unit to measure tensile strength?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "pounds per square inch",
                "joules per square metre",
                "megapascals",
                "watts per hour"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["megapascals"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "What is one function of the slag produced from electrode coatings?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Add more nitrogen and oxygen to the weld.",
                "Help maintain the arc.",
                "Add alloying elements to the weld deposit.",
                "Prevent the weld from cooling too rapidly."
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Prevent the weld from cooling too rapidly."],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "What is the main purpose for keeping low hydrogen electrodes dry?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "to assist in producing and maintaining a stable, smooth arc",
                "to minimize the possibility of hydrogen-induced cracking",
                "to increase the electrode's deposition rate",
                "to increase the shelf life of the electrodes in storage"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["to minimize the possibility of hydrogen-induced cracking"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Which electrode would be the best choice if the base metal properties were unknown?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "E7018",
                "E7014",
                "E6011",
                "E7024"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["E7018"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "What is the approximate length of a normal arc?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "same as the outside diameter of the electrode",
                "half the thickness of the base metal",
                "twice the thickness of the core wire",
                "same as the diameter of the core wire"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["same as the diameter of the core wire"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "What happens when you increase the arc length?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "amperage increases and voltage increases",
                "amperage decreases and voltage increases",
                "amperage increases and voltage decreases",
                "amperage decreases and voltage decreases"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["amperage decreases and voltage increases"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "What happens when you decrease the arc length?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "deeply penetrating, narrow bead with more build-up",
                "deeply penetrating, shallow bead with less build-up",
                "shallow penetrating, wide bead with less build-up",
                "no significant change in the weld"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["deeply penetrating, narrow bead with more build-up"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Which acronym pertains to the 5 basic weld joints?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "NEMAA",
                "BCTEL",
                "ACHFC",
                "NHLPA"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["BCTEL"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "On what type of joint would you most likely find groove welds?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Edge",
                "Butt",
                "Fillet",
                "Lap"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Butt"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Why is it sometimes necessary to bevel joint edges prior to welding?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "to prevent distortion",
                "to obtain complete penetration",
                "to make the job last longer",
                "to provide a clear line to follow when welding"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["to obtain complete penetration"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Which types of groove welds require only one member of the joint to be prepared?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "square and bevel",
                "Vee and J",
                "bevel and J",
                "U and J"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["bevel and J"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "What does the 3 represent when interpreting the 3F position?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "3 passes required",
                "overhead position",
                "a 3rd year apprentice is allowed to weld this joint",
                "vertical position"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["vertical position"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Which term describes a material that shows no permanent distortion before failure?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "brittleness",
                "hardness",
                "toughness",
                "elasticity"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["brittleness"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Which statement describes a non-ferrous metal?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "high iron content and usually magnetic",
                "high iron content and usually non-magnetic",
                "contains little or no iron and is usually magnetic",
                "contains little or no iron and is usually non-magnetic"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["contains little or no iron and is usually non-magnetic"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "How can using a new hand-held file give you an estimate of a metal's hardness?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "If you tap the metal with the file, hardened tool steel will not ring.",
                "If the file bites into the metal easily, it is likely a hard material.",
                "If the file bites into the metal easily, it is likely a soft material.",
                "If the metal is harder than the file, the file bites in easily."
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["If the file bites into the metal easily, it is likely a soft material."],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "For efficient cutting operations, oxygen must have a minimum purity of:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "80%",
                "93%",
                "95.5%",
                "99.5%"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["99.5%"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "What is likely to happen if the cutting travel speed is too fast?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Productivity increases and your employer is very impressed.",
                "Slag bubbles to the surface and the cutting action eventually stops.",
                "The tip overheats and begins to backfire.",
                "A clean, slag-free cut is produced."
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Slag bubbles to the surface and the cutting action eventually stops."],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "If a shop switched from acetylene to propane gas for cutting, it would be necessary to:",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "Purchase all new cutting torches.",
                "Install special fuel gas regulators.",
                "Check with the manufacturer to determine if the equipment is compatible.",
                "Change to larger size hoses."
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["Check with the manufacturer to determine if the equipment is compatible."],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Manufacturers design this device in a welding machine to have a certain number of turns of wire.",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "circuit",
                "core",
                "coil",
                "cycle"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["coil"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "How is electrode positive abbreviated?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "DCSP",
                "DCRP",
                "AC",
                "ACHF"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["DCRP"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "Which electrode has a cellulose coating?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "E6010",
                "E6013",
                "E7014",
                "E7018"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["E6010"],
            "explanation": ""
        },
        {
            "id": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "topicId": "a9ef6a17-f5c7-4b94-848f-94f17c29b8c4",
            "question": "What happens when you decrease the arc length?",
            "type": "single_type",
            "options": [
                "deeply penetrating, narrow bead with more build-up",
                "deeply penetrating, shallow bead with less build-up",
                "shallow penetrating, wide bead with less build-up",
                "no significant change in the weld"
            ],
            "correctAnswer": ["deeply penetrating, narrow bead with more build-up"],
            "explanation": ""
        }
    ]
}

